Finding Aid for the Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2011
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2011
Mus. Arc. 56
Haupt, Irene
1 DVD (70 digital images in tiff format)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Contains 70 digital images of musicians who participated in the June in Buffalo Festival 2011 at the University at Buffalo.
All files in the collection renamed to reflect chronological sequence. Renamed files stored with the collection on a separate DVD.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Administrative Information
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Irene Haupt, 2011.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
The entire collection of images from June in Buffalo 2011 is available in University at Buffalo Libraries Digital Collections.
Biographical Note
Irene Haupt, a graduate of the State University of New York at Buffalo, has been documenting the Buffalo arts scene through her photography since 1976. During that time she has worked for, or with, some of the most notable institutions in Buffalo, including the Irish Classical Theatre, Studio Arena Theater, the Kavinoky Theatre, the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, the Theatre of Youth, the Albright-Knox Art Gallery, and the State University of New York at Buffalo. In addition to her specialty of theater photography, Irene Haupt has also devoted much of her career to the photography of musicians and musical events. Most notable is her documentation of the contemporary music scene in Buffalo, including coverage of the University at Buffalo's June in Buffalo festival of new music, 1982-1987, and 2000 to the present. Over the course of those years, she has created a visual record that contains images of some of the most significant composers and performers of the last quarter century. The list of names is impressive: Aaron Copland, Morton Feldman, Leo Smit, Virgil Thomson, Steve Reich, Ralph Shapey, Henry Brant, Earle Brown, Ursula Oppens, Jan Williams, Lukas Foss, Philip Glass, Otto Luening, Conlon Nancarrow, Ernst Krenek, Larry Austin, Lejaren Hiller, Elliott Carter, Milton Babbitt, John Cage, Charles Wuorinen, Jacob Druckman, and Yvar Mikhashoff, among others.
The June in Buffalo festival of contemporary music was begun at the University at Buffalo in 1975 by composer Morton Feldman. He directed the festival 1975-1978 and in 1980. The festival was dormant from 1981 through 1985. David Felder revived the festival in 1986 and has been its director since that time.
Scope and Content Note
The collection of Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2011 contains 70 digital images of participants in the festival for 2011. The list of musicians includes David Felder, Brad Lubman, Jean Kopperud, Tom Kolor, Eric Chaslow, James Baker, Eric Huebner, Ensemble Linea, Edmund Campion, Hilda Paredes, Irvine Arditti, Jeffrey Stadelman, Signal Ensemble, Magnus Andersson, Jon Nelson and the Genkin Philharmonic, Jonathan Golove, and the Slee Sinfonietta.
Arrangement
One series arranged chronologically.
Container List
- James Baker conducting a rehearsal of David Felder's work, Requiescat, with the Slee Sinfonietta at June in Buffalo 2011, 2010-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_01.jpg)
- Percussionist Tom Kolor and clarinetist Jean Kopperud rehearsing David Felder's work, Requeiscat, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_02.jpg)
- Violinist Maureen Yuen, guitarist Magnus Andersson, violist Adrienne Elisha, and violoncellist Jonathan Golove rehearsing David Felder's work, Requiescat, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_03.jpg)
- Slee Sinfonietta rehearsing David Felder's work, Requiescat, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_04.jpg)
- James Baker conducting a rehearsal of David Felder's work, Requeiscat, with Slee Sinfonietta at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_05.jpg)
- Electromagnetically prepared piano at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-08, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_053.jpg)
- James Baker conducting a rehearsal of David Felder's work, Requiescat, with Slee Sinfonietta at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_06.jpg)
- Still image from Elliot Caplan's video for David Felder's work, Shamayim, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-09, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_063.jpg)
- James Baker conducting percussionist Tom Kolor and other members of Slee Sinfonietta in a rehearsal of David Felder's work, Requiescat, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_07.jpg)
- Composer David Felder, conductor James Baker, violoncellist Jonathan Golove, clarinetist Jean Kopperud, and violist Adrienne Elisha rehearsing Felder's work, Requiescat, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_08.jpg)
- Conductor James Baker and pianist Eric Huebner in a rehearsal of David Felder's work, Requiescat, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_09.jpg)
- Clarinetist Jean Kopperud, composer Eric Chasalow, and pianist Eric Huebner at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_10.jpg)
- Guitarist Magnus Andersson at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_11.jpg)
- Pianists Steve Beck and Eric Huebner at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_12.jpg)
- Composer Eric Chasalow at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_13.jpg)
- Composer Eric Chasalow at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_14.jpg)
- Pianist Eric Huebner and percussionist Tom Kolor rehearsing Edmund Campion's work, Domus Aurea, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_15.jpg)
- James Baker conducting a rehearsal of Eric Chasalow's work, Suspicious Motives, with flutist Barry Crawford, clarinetist Jean Kopperud, violinist Yuki Numata, and violoncellist Jonathan Golove at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_16.jpg)
- Pianist Steve Beck and percussionist Jon Hepfer rehearsing Friedrich Kern's work, Eins Zwei, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-05, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_17.jpg)
- Composer Edmund Campion at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_18.jpg)
- Composer Edmund Campion at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_19.jpg)
- Composers David Felder and Edmund Campion at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_20.jpg)
- Composer Eric Chasalow presenting a lecture at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_21.jpg)
- Composer Eric Chasalow presenting a lecture at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_22.jpg)
- Student composer Chun Ting Pang with Ensemble Linea during a rehearsal of Pang's work, When the Rain is Dissolving the Clouds, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_23.jpg)
- Composer Hilda Paredes with violinist Yuki Numata, violoncellist Jonathan Golove, and pianist Eric Huebner during a rehearsal of her work, Alegoria Tri-partita, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_24.jpg)
- Composer Hilda Paredes with violoncellist Jonathan Golove and violinist Yuki Numata in a rehearsal of her work, Alegoria Tri-partita, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_25.jpg)
- Ensemble Linea at June in Buffalo 2011. Back row left to right: Andrea Nagy, Maiko Matsuoka, Johannes Burghoff, Keiko Murakami. Front row left to right: Olivier Maurel, Genevieve Letang, Jean-Philippe Wurtz, Reto Staub., 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_26.jpg)
- Student composers at June in Buffalo 2011: Jeff Roberts (outside railing), Matthew Sargent, Francisco Castillo Trigueros, Michael Thomas Foumai, David Carter, Jacob Gotlib, Paul Clift, Amadeus Regucera, Sivan Eldar, Brian Mark, Friedrich Heinrich Kern, Ethan Hayden, Chappell Kingsland, Cherise Leiter, Matthew Goodheart, Nathan Heidelberger, Brian Penkrot (outside right railing, back), and Leeds Barroll (outside right railing, front), 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_27.jpg)
- Trumpet player Jon Nelson at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_28.jpg)
- Composer Jeffrey Stadelman with trumpet player Jon Nelson and pianist Eric Huebner at a rehearsal of Stadelman's work, Mr. Natural, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_29.jpg)
- Student composer Jeff Roberts in a rehearsal of his work, Breaking Bamboo, Shaking Jade, with flutist Barry Crawford, pianist Steve Beck, and percussionist Jon Hepfer at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_30.jpg)
- Student composer Ethan Hayden and composer Hilda Paredes at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_31.jpg)
- Composer Jeffrey Stadelman in a workshop with student composers at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_32.jpg)
- Composer Eric Chasalow in a workshop with student composers at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_33.jpg)
- Composer Edmund Campion performing his work, Roulette, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_34.jpg)
- Composer Eric Chasalow with guitarist Magnus Andersson at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_35.jpg)
- Conductor Brad Lubman and Signal Ensemble in a workshop at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_36.jpg)
- Clarinetist Jean Kopperud performing Eric Chasalow's work, In a Manner of Speaking, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_37.jpg)
- Pianist Eric Huebner and trumpet player Jon Nelson performing Jeffrey Stadelman's work, Mr. Natural, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_38.jpg)
- Student composer Jacob Gotlib in a rehearsal of his work, Year Without Summer, with members of Ensemble Linea, violoncellist Johannes Burghoff and conductor Jean-Philippe Wurtz, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-07, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_39.jpg)
- James Baker conducting the Slee Sinfonietta in a rehearsal of David Felder's work, Requiescat, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-07, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_40.jpg)
- James Baker conducting the Slee Sinfonietta in a rehearsal of David Felder's work, Requiescat, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-07, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_41.jpg)
- Composer David Felder at sound console with Christopher Jacobs and J. T. Rinker in a rehearsal at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-07, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_42.jpg)
- Guitarist Magnus Andersson performing at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-07, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_43.jpg)
- James Baker conducting the Slee Sinfonietta in a performance of David Felder's work, Requiescat, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-07, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_44.jpg)
- Violinist Yuki Numata, violoncellist Jonathan Golove, and pianist Eric Huebner performing Hilda Paredes' work, Alegoria Tri-partita, at June in Buffalo 2011, with Steven Beck, page-turner, 2011-06-07, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_45.jpg)
- Composer Hilda Paredes with violinist Yuki Numata, violoncellist Jonathan Golove, and pianist Eric Huebner after a performance of Paredes' work, Alegoria Tri-partita, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-07, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_46.jpg)
- Clarinetist Jean Kopperud and percussionist Tom Kolor performing Jeffrey Stadelman's work, Wills and Wonts, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-07, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_47.jpg)
- Composer Jeffrey Stadelman with clarinetist Jean Kopperud and percussionist Tom Kolor after the performance of Stadelman's work, Wills and Wonts, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-07, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_48.jpg)
- James Baker conducting a performance of Eric Chasalow's work, Suspicious Motives, with violinist Yuki Numata, violoncellist Jonathan Golove, clarinetist Jean Kopperud, and flutist Barry Crawford at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_49.jpg)
- Composer Eric Chasalow with conductor James Baker, violinist Yuki Numata, violoncellist Jonathan Golove, clarinetist Jean Kopperud, and flutist Barry Crawford after the performance of Chasalow's work, Suspicious Motives, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-07, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_50.jpg)
- Conductor James Baker with clarinetist Greg Barrett, percussionist Tom Kolor, pianist Steve Beck, pianist Eric Huebner, violoncellist Jonathan Golove, and violoncellist Evelyn Farny at a performance of Jeffrey Stadelman's work, Incidental Music, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-07, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_51.jpg)
- Student composer Per Bloland in a workshop performance of his work, Negative Mirror II, with violinist Maiko Matsuoka, violoncellist Johannes Burghoff, clarinetist Andrea Nagy, flutist Keiko Murakami, and conductor Jean-Philippe Wurtz of Ensemble Linea at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-08, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_52.jpg)
- Percussionist Olivier Maurel of Ensemble Linea playing a melodica in a workshop at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-08, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_54.jpg)
- Pianist Reto Staub of Ensemble Linea at an electronically prepared piano in a workshop at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-08, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_55.jpg)
- Student composer Per Bloland in a workshop with pianist Reto Staub of Ensemble Linea at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-08, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_56.jpg)
- Student composer Francisco Castillo Trigueros and flutist Alice Teyssier of Slee Sinfonietta at a workshop performance of Trigueros' work, Nealika, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-08, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_57.jpg)
- Brad Lubman conducting a rehearsal with the Signal ensemble at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-08, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_58.jpg)
- Composer Hilda Paredes with violinist Irvine Arditti at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-08, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_59.jpg)
- Composer Hilda Paredes with violinist Irvine Arditti at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-08, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_60.jpg)
- Violinist Irvine Arditti at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-08, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_61.jpg)
- Pianist Eric Huebner and percussionist Tom Kolor performing Edmund Campion's work, Domus Aurea, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-08, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_62.jpg)
- Student composer Per Bloland setting up the electronically prepared piano at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-09, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_64.jpg)
- Ensemble Linea workshop at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-09, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_65.jpg)
- Still image from Elliot Caplan's video for David Felder's work, Shamayim, at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-10, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_66.jpg)
- Genkin Philharmonic performance at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-10, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_67.jpg)
- Genkin Philharmonic performance at June in Buffalo 2011, 2011-06-10, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_68.jpg)
- Ensemble Linea performing David Felder's work, Partial [Dist] res [s] toration, at June in Buffalo 2011. Players from left to right: Reto Staub, Keiko Murakami, Andrea Nagy, Johannes Burghoff, Maiko Matsuoka, Olivier Maurel, with conductor Jean-Philippe Wurtz., 2011-06-11, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_69.jpg)
- Composer David Felder with Ensemble Linea after the performance of his work, Partial [Dist] res [s] toration, at June in Buffalo 2011. Players from left to right: Reto Staub, Keiko Murakami, Andrea Nagy, Johannes Burghoff, Maiko Matsuoka, Olivier Maurel, with conductor Jean-Philippe Wurtz., 2011-06-11, 1 digital image (tiff format) (Image-file jib2011_70.jpg)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
June in Buffalo (Festival) (Buffalo, N.Y.)--Photographs; Composers--Photographs; Music festivals--New York (State)--Buffalo--Photographs; Musicians--Photographs
Genres
Digital photographs; Portrait photographs
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2000
Mus. Arc. 18
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2000 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2001
Mus. Arc. 19
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2001 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2002
Mus. Arc. 20
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2002 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2003
Mus. Arc. 21
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2003 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2004
Mus. Arc. 25
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2004 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2005
Mus. Arc. 27
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2005 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2006
Mus. Arc. 29
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2006 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2007
Mus. Arc. 38
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2007 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2008
Mus. Arc. 39
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2008 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2009
Mus. Arc. 50
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2009 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2010
Mus. Arc. 55
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2010 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2012
Mus. Arc. 60
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2012 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2013
Mus. Arc. 66
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2013 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2014
Mus. Arc. 67
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2014 June in Buffalo.
June in Buffalo Photograph Collection
A selection of images from the June in Buffalo festivals is available through University at Buffalo Libraries Digital Collections.